<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Perspective on My Art Gallery</title><link>https://prajaktagd.github.io/tags/perspective/</link><description>Recent content in Perspective on My Art Gallery</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 20:08:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prajaktagd.github.io/tags/perspective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three Point Perspective Drawing</title><link>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/26-oct-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 20:08:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/26-oct-22/</guid><description>In three point perspective parallel lines along the width of an object meet at two separate points on the horizon and vertical lines on the object meet at a point on the perpendicular bisector of the horizon line.
It uses three sets of orthogonal lines and three vanishing points to draw an object. It is used to show epic height or depth to an object.
To draw in three point perspective, start with two vanishing points on the horizon and third vanishing point on the perpendicular bisector (usually far from the horizon).</description></item><item><title>Two Point Perspective Drawing</title><link>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/15-oct-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 12:10:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/15-oct-22/</guid><description>In two point perspective drawings, objects converge on two vanishing points. The vanishing points are placed on horizon line. The parallel lines that recedes to the vanishing points are called orthogonal lines.
To draw in two point perspective, start with two vanishing points on the horizon and a vertical line. The vertical line makes the corner of the object. Further draw lines from the end points of the vertical line to the vanishing points.</description></item><item><title>Freehand straight lines and circles</title><link>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/29-sept-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:18:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/29-sept-22/</guid><description>I am practicing freehand straight lines and circles. It will help me draw perspective drawings smoothly. Tip- Don&amp;rsquo;t draw straight lines or circles going forward and backward. Draw in single shot where you know your starting and ending point.</description></item><item><title>Eye Level in perspective drawings</title><link>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/14-sept-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 21:50:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/14-sept-22/</guid><description>Started reading book on perspective drawings called &amp;lsquo;Perspective Made Easy&amp;rsquo; by Ernest R. Norling.
Horizon is the height of our eyes no matter where we are above the ground, so we can say that horizon is nothing but our eye level.
The perspective changes when we see at eye level, above the eye level or below the eye level.
So, while drawing consider the horizon at your eye level and where you see(above, below or same) based on that, draw.</description></item><item><title>One point perspective drawing</title><link>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/7-sept-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 21:08:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://prajaktagd.github.io/post/7-sept-22/</guid><description>One point perspective is a drawing method used to draw objects on a flat drawing surface so that they look three-dimensional and realistic. It shows how things appear to get smaller when they get away, converging to a single vanishing point.
In one point perspective drawing, all non-vertical and non-horizontal lines vanish into a single point called vanishing point which is placed on the horizon line often in the center of the picture(not necessary).</description></item></channel></rss>